export const PHYSICSA2018 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The number 2.40 x 10-5 has how many significant figures?",
A: "2",
B: "3",
C: "4",
D: "5",
answer: "B. 3",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. The total area under a force-velocity graph represents",
A: "energy.",
B: "impulse.",
C: "power.",
D: "pressure.",
answer: "C. power.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Which of the following pairs of quantities will determine the momentum of a body?",
A: "Mass and weight",
B: "Weight and acceleration",
C: "Mass and velocity",
D: "Accelerations and velocity",
answer: "C. Mass and velocity",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Which of the following quantities is not fundamental?",
A: "Electric current",
B: "Mass",
C: "Luminous intensity",
D: "Velocity",
answer: "D. Velocity",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. When salt is dissolved in water, the freezing point of the water",
A: "decreases.",
B: "increases.",
C: "remains constant.",
D: "increases and later decreases.",
answer: "A. decreases.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Images formed by diverging mirrors are always",
A: "inverted",
B: "magnified.",
C: "real.",
D: "virtual.",
answer: "D. virtual.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Which of the following bodies is luminous?",
A: "Comet",
B: "Moon",
C: "Sun",
D: "Meteor",
answer: "C. Sun",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Which of the following radiations has a frequency lower than that of infra-red radiation?",
A: "Gamma rays",
B: "Radio waves",
C: "Ultra-violet rays",
D: "X-rays",
answer: "B. Radio waves",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. The accurate value of the electromotive force of a cell is determined by a/an",
A: "ammeter.",
B: "meter bridge.",
C: "voltmeter.",
D: "potentiometer.",
answer: "D. potentiometer.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Volume is the measure of",
A: "how much matter an object contains.",
B: "how much space an object occupies.",
C: "the area of the outside surface of an object.",
D: "the degree of compression of the materials of an object.",
answer: "B. how much space an object occupies",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. The force of attraction between molecules of the same kind is",
A: "cohesion.",
B: "capillarity.",
C: "upthrust.",
D: "adhesion.",
answer: "A. cohesion.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Water can be made to boil below 100°C by",
A: "increasing its exposed surface to the atmosphere.",
B: "decreasing its exposed surface to the atmosphere.",
C: "reducing its pressure at the surface.",
D: "adding impurities to it.",
answer: "C. reducing its pressure at the surface.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Given the coefficient of linear expansion of gold is 14.3 x I o-, what is its coefficient of cubic expansion?",
A: "2.86x10-8/°C",
B: "4.29x10-8/°C",
C: "2.86x 10-7/°C",
D: "4.29x107 /°C",
answer: "D. 4.29x107 /°C",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. What is the potential difference across the 6.0 Ω resistor in the diagram below?",
A: "4.8 v",
B: "6.4 v",
C: "9.0 v",
D: "15.0",
answer: "A. 4.8 v",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. A single force that has the same effect as two or more forces acting at a point on a body is called a/an",
A: "equilibrant force.",
B: "gravitational force.",
C: "parallel force.",
D: "resultant force.",
answer: "D. resultant force.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. The mass number of an element is 28 and the number of neutrons in its nucleus is 7. What is the atomic number of the element?",
A: "4",
B: "21",
C: "35",
D: "196",
answer: "B. 21",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Which of the following statements about current electricity is not correct?",
A: "The algebraic sum of the currents at a junction of a circuit is zero.",
B: "Resistors connected in series in a circuit have the same current.",
C: "Resistors connected in parallel in a circuit have the same current.",
D: "Conductors provide resistance to the flow of current.",
answer: "B. Resistors connected in series in a circuit have the same current.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. A force of 6N due north and another 8N due west act on a point 0. What is the magnitude of the resultant of the two forces?",
A: "2 N",
B: "14 N",
C: "10 N",
D: "48 N",
answer: "C. 10 N",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. The property a material possesses for which it can be drawn into sheets is",
A: "elasticity.",
B: "ductility.",
C: "malleability.",
D: "tensile strain",
answer: "C. malleability",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. The Tesla is the unit of",
A: "magnetic field intensity.",
B: "magnetic flux.",
C: "magnetic flux density.",
D: "inductance",
answer: "A. magnetic field intensity.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. What mass of water will liberate 4200 joules of heat as the water cools from 90°C to 80°C?  [specific heat capacity of water=4.2 Jkg /°C]",
A: "10 kg",
B: "50 kg",
C: "100 kg",
D: "420 kg",
answer: "C. 100 kg",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. A body falling vertically falls with",
A: "uniform velocity.",
B: "uniform speed.",
C: "constant acceleration.",
D: "variable acceleration.",
answer: "C. constant acceleration",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. The center of gravity of a body is the",
A: "weight of the body.",
B: "point at which forces act on the body.",
C: "point on the object where its weight always act.",
D: "point at which the weight is less concentrated.",
answer: "C. point on the object where its weight always act.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. The viscous force on a body falling in a viscous liquid",
A: "decreases as the speed of the body increases.",
B: "Increases as the speed of the body increases.",
C: "increases as the speed of the body decreases.",
D: "remains constant as the body moves",
answer: "B. Increases as the speed of the body increases.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The positive electrode of an electric cell is called the",
A: "anode.",
B: "cathode.",
C: "dielectric.",
D: "electrolyte.",
answer: "A. anode.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. When a stone falls through a viscous liquid, the viscous force acts",
A: "parallel to the direction of the stone’s motion.",
B: "perpendicularly to the direction of the stone’s motion.",
C: "opposite to the direction of the stone’s motion.",
D: "tangentially to the direction of the stone’s motion.",
answer: "A. parallel to the direction of the stone’s motion",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Which of the following actions will produce a positive charge?",
A: "Rubbing a glass rod with silk.",
B: "Rubbing an ebonite rod with silk,",
C: "Connecting two positively charged wires in a circuit.",
D: "Connecting two negatively charged wires",
answer: "A. Rubbing a glass rod with silk",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Which of the following-colored surfaces will best absorb radiant energy?",
A: "Black",
B: "Red",
C: "White",
D: "Yellow",
answer: "A. Black",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The metric prefix designated by the decimal multiple one million is",
A: "kilo",
B: "mega",
C: "giga",
D: "atto",
answer: "B. mega",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. In simple harmonic motion, the frequency of oscillation is the inverse of the",
A: "amplitude.",
B: "period.",
C: "speed.",
D: "wavelength.",
answer: "B. period.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. An object is placed 15 cm in front of a converging mirror of radius of curvature 40 cm. The image of the object formed by the mirror is",
A: "virtual, erect and magnified.",
B: "real, inverted and magnified.",
C: "virtual, inverted and magnified.",
D: "real, erect and magnified.",
answer: "A. virtual, erect and magnified.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. When a gas is compressed in a container at constant temperature, the molecules of the gas",
A: "slightly increase in size.",
B: "make more impact per unit time on the walls of the container.",
C: "move at the same speed so that the pressure remains unchanged.",
D: "move faster so that the pressure will increase.",
answer: "B. make more impact per unit time on the walls of the container",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Which of the following statements indicates Charles’ law? For a given sample of gas, the volume is",
A: "directly proportional to pressure at constant temperature.",
B: "inversely proportional to pressure at constant temperature.",
C: "directly proportional to temperature at constant pressure.",
D: "inversely proportional to temperature at constantan pressure.",
answer: "C. directly proportional to temperature at constant pressure",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. A machine containing five pulleys is 60% efficient. What effort is required by the machine to lift a load of 900 N?",
A: "3 N",
B: "30 N",
C: "300 N",
D: "3,000 N",
answer: "C. 300 N",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Two particles are said to be in phase during wave propagation when they",
A: "have the same displacement and are moving in opposite directions.",
B: "have the same displacement and are moving in the same direction.",
C: "are moving with the same speed in opposite directions.",
D: "are moving with the same speed in the same direction.",
answer: "C. are moving with the same speed in opposite directions",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. All of the following statements about a freely falling body are true except its",
A: "initial velocity is zero.",
B: "initial acceleration is zero.",
C: "speed increases as time progresses.",
D: "acceleration remains constant as it falls.",
answer: "C. speed increases as time progresses",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. The time rate of change in momentum is",
A: "force.",
B: "impulse.",
C: "power.",
D: "pressure.",
answer: "A. force.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. A stone sinks while a feather floats when dropped in water. Which of the following statements best explains this phenomenon?",
A: "The feather is denser than the stone.",
B: "The upthrust on the feather is greater than that on the stone.",
C: "The water is denser than the stone.",
D: "The density of the water is greater than that of the feather.",
answer: "D. The density of the water is greater than that of the feather.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. The latent heat of a substance depends on the substance’s",
A: "mass and temperature.",
B: "nature and temperature.",
C: "mass and nature.",
D: "temperature only.",
answer: "A. mass and temperature",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. The product of the electric field intensity and the magnitude of the charge placed in the electric field can be expressed in",
A: "coulombs.",
B: "joules.",
C: "newtons.",
D: "volts.",
answer: "C. newtons.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. A series circuit consists of a battery whose output is 12 v, a resistor of resistance 2Ωs and an ammeter. What will be the ammeter’s reading when the circuit is closed?",
A: "0.5 A",
B: "6.0 A",
C: "24.0 A",
D: "48.0 A",
answer: "B. 6.0 A",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. The focal length of a spherical mirror is 12 cm. What is the radius of curvature of the mirror?",
A: "6cm",
B: "12cm",
C: "24cm",
D: "36cm",
answer: "B. 12cm",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. What type of motion is performed when a church drum is strucked?",
A: "Circular motion",
B: "Random motion",
C: "Oscillatory motion",
D: "Vibratory motion",
answer: "D. Vibratory motion",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. The equation 𝑢2𝑠𝑖𝑛2𝜃𝑔 is used to determine the",
A: "total time of flight of a projectile.",
B: "range of a projectile.",
C: "maximum height of a projectile.",
D: "time of projection of a projectile",
answer: "B. range of a projectile.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. The velocity ratio of a block and tackle system is determined by its",
A: "efficiency.",
B: "Work output.",
C: "Work input.",
D: "number of pulleys.",
answer: "D. number of pulleys.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. The total capacitance c of three capacitors that are connected in series in a circuit can be determined by the equation:",
A: "*******************************",
B: "*******************************",
C: "*******************************",
D: "*******************************",
answer: "Z. zzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "Z",
correctOption: 9,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. Which of the following waves is longitudinal?",
A: "Light waves",
B: "Sound waves",
C: "Radio waves",
D: "Water waves",
answer: "B. Sound waves",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. Which of the following processes may occur at any temperature?",
A: "Boiling",
B: "Evaporation",
C: "Freezing",
D: "Melting",
answer: "B. Evaporation",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. How many liters are there in 0.05kL?",
A: "0.5 L",
B: "5.0 L",
C: "50.0 L",
D: "500.0 L",
answer: "C. 50.0 L",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. Which of the following radiations has the longest wavelength?",
A: "X-ray",
B: "Infra-red ray",
C: "Radio waves",
D: "Gamma ray",
answer: "C. Radio waves",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},


]